Anshul Virmani

LEAD PRODUCT MANAGER

Profile

With 10 years of expertise in leading Product & Analytics, I specialize in developing and launching customer-facing products across areas such as retail e-commerce, travel and edtech. Drove digital transformation in customer engagement, significantly enhancing online transactions and omnichannel growth, aligning with goals to improve in-store journeys and checkout experiences.

Work History

Lead Product Manager, Accel backed ed-tech startup, Dubai

APRIL 2021 - DECEMBER 2023

- Spearheaded the development and launch of innovative online learning
 platforms, Pixical Piano and Chess, leading a cross-functional team of 7 through
 strategic market pivots. Achieved a significant shift in target demographics from
 children to adult learners, in response to post-COVID market dynamics.
- Innovated with the integration of an AI-powered chatbot to enhance student onboarding and engagement on the Chess platform, resulting in a 20% improvement in conversion by efficient query resolution.
- Collaborated with over 20 chess experts to design a specialized curriculum for adult learners, leading to a 30% faster improvement in chess ratings.
- Achieved a 15% increase in Lifetime Value (LTV) by launching a unified subscription model that offered access to over 50 skills, significantly enhancing our value proposition
- Implemented systematic refinements to the coaching framework through continuous experimentation, achieving a 23% improvement in first-month user retention.

Senior Product Manager, Landmark Group

SEPTEMBER 2018 - APRIL 2021

- Spearheaded the Customer Engagement and Loyalty Squad, focusing on harmonizing online and offline shopping experiences, aligning with digital product enhancements for in-store journeys.
- Boosted Shukran's online transaction rate from 15% to 51% for eight Landmark brands by refining the account linking process, contributing to a seamless integration of digital and physical retail operations.
- Implemented data-driven improvements in Shukran's e-commerce onboarding process, resulting in a 16% increase in the omnichannel customer base, supporting the goal of optimizing in-store customer checkout experiences.
- Led a Proof of Concept (PoC) with a third-party Customer Data Platform (CDP) vendor, aimed at achieving a unified customer view for personalized experiences.
- Led product initiatives to enhance the Content Management Systems (CMS),
 achieving a substantial reduction in web content go-live time from 14 to 7 days.

Senior Product Manager, Cleartrip Pvt Ltd

APRIL 2015 - AUGUST 2018

 Led product development and growth initiatives for hotels and activities, specializing in conversion rate optimization and improving customer experiences.

Details

Dubai
United Arab Emirates
+971 56 713 6238
anshul.virmani88@gmail.com

Links

LinkedIn

Skills

Product Management

Product Strategy

Data Management and Analytics

Customer Driven Decision Making

Agile Development Methodology

Stakeholder Management

Collaboration Skills

Attention to Detail

Leadership Experience

Languages

English

- Led the development of a 'Price Autocorrection' engine with an objective to match rate plans with competitors and introduce missing ones, resulting in a 20% revenue growth and expanding hotel rate plan coverage from 35% to 85%.
- Redesigned the supplier platform for improved usability and digital experience, engaging over 14,000 hoteliers and contributing to a 10% increase in bookings, driven by market research.
- Achieved a 6% uplift in hotel booking conversion rates by implementing data-driven recommendation features on the hotel Search Results Page (SRP).
- Contributed to the development and launch of a new business vertical "Local", intending to provide users with seamless discovery and booking of local
 experiences.

Product Analyst, eBay, Inc., Bengaluru

APRIL 2014 - FEBRUARY 2015

- Managed A/B testing initiatives focused on Cart conversion improvements, utilizing in-depth analysis of customer needs to inform and recommend effective enhancements and improve key business performance indicators.
- Spearheaded the introduction of the pragmatic Progressive Checkout platform in Germany by analyzing data, achieving a significant 10% increase in checkout conversion rates through innovative product solutions.
- Received the 'Commerce Experience' award, acknowledging rapid ramp-up and exceptional delivery, highlighting a strong commitment to excellence, motivating results, and expertise in web technologies.

Business Analyst, EXL Services, Gurgaon

JUNE 2011 - JUNE 2012

- Monitored and analyzed the performance of multiple European portfolios for a Fortune 100 banking client, focusing on reducing default losses and enhancing portfolio health & achieving other success metrics.
- Conceptualized and implemented an automation tool for managing a £1.8 billion portfolio, resulting in a 12.5% reduction in man-hours.
- Managed a £2.82 billion portfolio as the sole analyst within just three months of joining, showcasing rapid adaptation and flexible portfolio management skills.

Education

Masters of Business Administration (MBA), Indian Institute of Management, Lucknow

JULY 2012 - JULY 2014

Bachelor of Engineering, PEC University of Technology, Chandigarh

JULY 2007 - MAY 2011

Certifications

Professional Scrum Product Owner (PSPO) 1

Professional Scrum Master (PSM) 1